<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Employment on gself</title>
    <link>https://gself.com/tags/employment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Employment on gself</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>George Self</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gself.com/tags/employment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Coach</title>
      <link>https://gself.com/2018/10/30/career-coach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gself.com/2018/10/30/career-coach/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionDuring the summer of 2018, Cochise College quietly launched our new Career Coach site. This is linked on the college’s homepage and is available to anyone who wants to explore careers and the training that Cochise College offers for career changes. Following is the Career Coach start page.
Folks can jump in and start searching for careers or for programs offered at Cochise College, but it is recommended that they begin by taking an assessment to determine what sort of career may be a good match for their skills and interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Completions and Jobs</title>
      <link>https://gself.com/2018/10/02/comp-and-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gself.com/2018/10/02/comp-and-jobs/</guid>
      <description>The following table is a completion report for Cochise College where various programs are linked to a job analysis. For example, in the field of education, we had 23 completers in 2003 and 147 in 2017, for a 539% increase. There were 372 annual openings at a median hourly salary of $18.21. To be sure, most education jobs require degrees higher than an Associate’s, but this information is at least an indicator of the likelihood of success for our graduating students whether they continue to pursue an education degree or seek work as an education paraprofessional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cochise County Economic Overview</title>
      <link>https://gself.com/2018/09/28/cc-econ-overvw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gself.com/2018/09/28/cc-econ-overvw/</guid>
      <description>I produced an EMSI Economic Overview of Cochise County and attached the results below. This is a thorough 25-page report and includes information on Cochise County’s population, cost of living, employment, Gross Regional Product, and many other interesting bits of economic information. You will enjoy reading this and can use it as a reference for projects that you may be working on.
Cochise County Economic Overview</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top and Bottom Growth Occupations</title>
      <link>https://gself.com/2018/09/25/growth-occ/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gself.com/2018/09/25/growth-occ/</guid>
      <description>I’m continuing my exploration of EMSI occupational data and wanted to share another tidbit, the top and bottom occupations for Cochise County by the growth in job postings between 2013 and 2017. For example, “Grounds Maintenance Workers” had 328 job postings in 2013 and 456 in 2017 for an increase of 39%. Here are the top growth jobs (sorted by the percent change in postings).
{&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration vs. Unemployment</title>
      <link>https://gself.com/2018/09/07/reg-vs-unemp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gself.com/2018/09/07/reg-vs-unemp/</guid>
      <description>There is a common belief among community college administrators that as unemployment rates increase the number of registrations for classes at the community college also increase. The idea is that students who are unemployed look to a community college for new training opportunities that may lead to future employment.
I wanted to look at that concept and created the following visualization to explore the idea.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>