<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Random Synaptic Firings</title>
    <link>https://gself.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Random Synaptic Firings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>George Self</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gself.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Our IPEDS Peers</title>
      <link>https://gself.com/2018/08/24/2018-08-24-intro-to-ipeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gself.com/2018/08/24/2018-08-24-intro-to-ipeds/</guid>
      <description>IPEDS Peer ComparisonFor my first blog post, I decided to take a look at a data extract from the Integrated Postsecondary Education System (IPEDS) data made available to Cochise College by the National Center for Education Statistics (NCES). All colleges and universities in the United States submit a huge amount of data to the IPEDS database every year so this is a vast repository of data about the entire higher education community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Day!</title>
      <link>https://gself.com/2018/08/21/2018-08-21-moving-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gself.com/2018/08/21/2018-08-21-moving-day/</guid>
      <description>The Start of Something Big!I was recently transferred from the Cochise College Institutional Research department to Special Assistant to the Provost. In this new role, I have been given a good bit of freedom to explore the college’s data and look for interesting relationships and other facts. I have a number of tools available to me, including SQL, R, Tableau, and Rapid-Miner. However, for simplicity, I’ve decided to focus the lion’s share of my time and talent (at least at first) on R and use the various R tools (like ggplot, plotly, and shiny) to explore and analyze data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://gself.com/2015/07/23/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gself.com/2015/07/23/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>