<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transfer on gself</title>
    <link>https://gself.com/tags/transfer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transfer on gself</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>George Self</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gself.com/tags/transfer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>University Transfer Student Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://gself.com/2018/09/18/2018-09-18-univ-trans-char/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gself.com/2018/09/18/2018-09-18-univ-trans-char/</guid>
      <description>The state of Arizona maintains a database that tracks students who transfer from one of our community colleges to one of our publicly-funded universities. That database includes a huge amount of information about transfer students and from time-to-time, I’ll share something from that database in my blog. For today, the following table lists some general characteristics about our transfer students over the past five years.
Characteristics12-1313-1414-1515-1616-1717-18ChangeTotal102671050710696108211085310257-0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Transfer</title>
      <link>https://gself.com/2018/09/11/2018-09-11-math-transfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gself.com/2018/09/11/2018-09-11-math-transfer/</guid>
      <description>The state of Arizona maintains a database, named ASSIST, that contains information about courses completed by students in public colleges/universities in Arizona. For example, if a student completed MAT 220, Calculus I, at Cochise College and another student completed MAT 243, Discrete Math Structures, at Arizona State University information about both of those classes would be stored in the ASSIST database. In addition, all of the classes completed by any Arizona student can be found so it is possible to “follow” Cochise College students to the University to see how well they are doing and, of course, how well we are doing in teaching those subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>